Guide to the John McCarthy Papers SC0524
Department of Special Collections and University Archives
John McCarthy papers
1951-2012
Department of Special Collections and University Archives
McCarthy, John, 1927-2011
SC0524
51.25 Linear Feet and 4577.28 megabytes
Correspondence, memos, reports, course materials, newsletters, articles, reprints, computer manuals, and other materials pertaining to McCarthy's research and his teaching at Stanford and MIT. Correspondents include Forest Baskett, Donald Knuth, Serge Lang, Joshua Lederberg, Douglas Lenat, Donald Michie, Hans Moravec, Zohar Manna, Aaron Sloman, and Masahiko Sato. Also included are correspondence, reprints, programs, notes, and articles from his work with Russian computer scientists, 1958-78.
Arrangement
The materials are arranged by accession.
Immediate Source of Acquisition note
Gift of John McCarthy, 1995-2009; Susan McCarthy, 2012-2013.
Information about Access
This collection is open for research.
Biographical/Historical Sketch
McCarthy was born on Sept. 4, 1927, in Boston. He earned his undergraduate degree from the California Institute of Technology in 1948 and his PhD at Princeton in 1951, both in mathematics. He was an instructor at Princeton from 1951 until 1953 when he came to Stanford as an assistant professor. In 1955, he left for Dartmouth and then for MIT before returning to Stanford for good in 1962 as a full professor of computer science.
During his remarkable career, McCarthy co-founded the MIT Artificial Intelligence Project and what became the Stanford Artificial Intelligence Lab, serving as director at Stanford from 1965 until 1980. He was named the first Charles M. Pigott Professor at the Stanford School of Engineering in 1987, before stepping down in 1994. He retired Jan. 1, 2001.
McCarthy was a giant in the field of computer science and a seminal figure in the field of artificial intelligence. While at Dartmouth in 1955, McCarthy authored a proposal for a two-month, 10-person summer research conference on "artificial intelligence" – the first use of the term in publication.
In proposing the conference, McCarthy wrote, "The study is to proceed on the basis of the conjecture that every aspect of learning or any other feature of intelligence can in principle be so precisely described that a machine can be made to simulate it." The subsequent conference is considered a watershed moment in computer science.
In 1958, McCarthy invented the computer programming language LISP, the second oldest programming language after FORTRAN. LISP is still used today and is the programming language of choice for artificial intelligence.
McCarthy also developed the concept of computer time-sharing in the late 1950s and early 1960s, an advance that greatly improved the efficiency of distributed computing and predated the era of cloud computing by decades.
In 1960, McCarthy authored a paper titled, "Programs with Common Sense," laying out the principles of his programming philosophy and describing "a system which is to evolve intelligence of human order."
McCarthy garnered attention in 1966 by hosting a series of four simultaneous computer chess matches carried out via telegraph against rivals in Russia. The matches, played with two pieces per side, lasted several months. McCarthy lost two of the matches and drew two. "They clobbered us," recalled Earnest.
Chess and other board games, McCarthy would later say, were the "Drosophila of artificial intelligence," a reference to the scientific name for fruit flies that are similarly important in the study of genetics.
McCarthy would later develop the first "hand-eye" computer system in which a computer was able to see real 3D blocks via a video camera and control a robotic arm to complete simple stacking and arrangement exercises.
The Association of Computing Machinery honored McCarthy with the A. M. Turing Award in 1971, the highest recognition in computer science. He received the Kyoto Prize in 1988 and the National Medal of Science in 1990, the nation's highest technical award. He was a member of the National Academy of Sciences, the National Academy of Engineering and the American Academy of Arts and Sciences.
McCarthy died on October 24, 2011. He was survived by his third wife, Carolyn Talcott of Stanford; two daughters, Susan McCarthy of San Francisco and Sarah McCarthy of Nevada City, Calif.; a son, Timothy Talcott McCarthy of Stanford; a brother, Patrick, of Los Angeles; two grandchildren, Kitty McCarthy of San Francisco and Joseph Gunther of New York City; and his first wife, Martha Coyote. McCarthy's second wife, Vera Watson, died in 1978 in a mountain-climbing accident attempting to scale Annapurna in Nepal.
Description of the Collection
Correspondence, memos, reports, course materials, newsletters, articles, reprints, computer manuals, and other materials pertaining to McCarthy's research and his teaching at Stanford and MIT. Correspondents include Forest Baskett, Donald Knuth, Serge Lang, Joshua Lederberg, Douglas Lenat, Donald Michie, Hans Moravec, Zohar Manna, Aaron Sloman, and Masahiko Sato. Also included are correspondence, reprints, programs, notes, and articles from his work with Russian computer scientists, 1958-78.
LISP (Computer program language); Computer programming.; Artificial intelligence.; McCarthy, John, 1927-2011; McCarthy, John, 1927-2011; Baskett, Forest.; Lang, Serge; Knuth, Donald Ervin, 1938-; Lederberg, Joshua; Lenat, Douglas B.; Stanford University. Computer Science Department. Faculty; Manna, Zohar.; Sloman, Aaron.; Michie, Donald.; Sato, Masahiko; Moravec, Hans P.
- Original Accession, Accession ARCH-1995-247
  - Future of Computing, 1978-1979 (memos) (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Academic Caucus on Foreign Policy, 1978 (memos) (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Accounting, 1975-1978 (memos, printouts - Stanford Artificial Intelligence Lab., computer usage) (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Advisees, 1979-1982 (memos, printouts) (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - ARPA - Advanced Research Projects Agency, 1976-1981 (memos, reports) (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - ATP Prize - Artificial Theorem Proving Prize, 1979-1983 (memos) (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Basic and Applied Research Panel, 1980-1981 (correspondence, memos, reports) (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Behavioral and Brain Sciences - beginning of an international journal of current research and theory with open peer commentary, 1977-1980 (correspondence, memos, articles, reprints) (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Campus Computing Bulletin, 1977-1979 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - CCS - Committee of Concerned Scientists, 1977-1982 (memos, correspondence, legal documents, articles, reports, reprints) (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - China, 1978-1979 (correspondence, articles) (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - CIS - Center for Integrated Systems, 1979-1981 (reports, memos, correspondence, minutes) (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Computer News Service, 1980 (letter, report) (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Computer Sci - Tech Board - Computer Science and Technology Board, 1980 (memos, correspondence, reports, minutes, articles) (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Concept, 1976, 1978 (article, commentary) (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Context, 1980-1981 (reports, memos, proposal), 1966 Oct-1967 Dec (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Core War - a two-person competitive game played in computer memory, 1977-1978 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Energy for 80's, 1980-1981, (newsletter, reports, memos, brochure, news release) (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Expense Reimbursement, 1976-1985 (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Finitary Search - Finite State Search Problems, 1976 (article), 1967-1968 (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - Grants, Proposals, Contracts, 1977-1982 (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - Heart - the artificial heart, 1983 (articles, correspondence, book chapters) (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - Human Rights, 1975-1978 (reports, correspondence, news releases, articles, newsletters) x-ref Committee of Concerned Scientists (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - Indoor Pollution, 1979-1980 (correspondence, articles, memos) (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Interstellar (reports, article) (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - IPL - Information Processing Letters, 1974, 1977 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - KL 20, 1975-1977 (correspondence, memos, newsletters, reports, minutes, brochure, printouts re computer equipment configuration for time-sharing) (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - KNOW - an axiomatization of knowledge, 1977 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - LOTS - Low Overhead Time-Sharing System, 1979 (memos, report) (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - LOTS, 1977-1978 (memos, correspondence, printouts, reports) (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - LOTS Memos, 1977-1979 (memos, reports) (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - LOTS Users, 1976-1977 (reports, memos), 1973 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Math Sci - Mathematical Sciences, 1979-1982 (reports, memos, course information booklet) (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Minima, 1976 (report on minimal inference) (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - N Queens - a mathematical problem, 1974-1982 (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - NLCPI - National Legal Center For the Public Interest, 1977-1979 (articles, newsletters, correspondence) (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - Notes, 1984 ( notes for a slide talk), 1958-1982 (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - Abstracts, 1977-1978 (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - AI Budget - Artificial Intelligence Budget, 1971-1974 (proposal, printouts, reports), 1972-1983 (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - AI for ARPA, 1973-1974 (memos, reports) (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - AI Journal, 1974-1979 (correspondence, reports, articles, abstracts) (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - Anti-Technology, 1972-1976) (articles, correspondence, notes) (Box 2, Folder 19)
  - Applicants, 1975-1979 (correspondence, resumes, memos), 1974 Nov (Box 2, Folder 20)
  - ARPA, 1973-1978 (reports, memos, articles) (Box 2, Folder 21)
  - Automation, 1972-1974 (correspondence, reports) (Box 2, Folder 22)
  - Axioms, 1972-1974 (reports, printouts, notes), 1977 (Box 2, Folder 23)
  - BAHTC - Bay Area Home Terminal Club, 1975 (articles, prospectus) (Box 2, Folder 24)
  - Bay Area Circle (on AI and Cognitive Science), 1975-1976 (memos) (Box 2, Folder 25)
  - Cars, 1972-1975 (correspondence, reports, articles) (Box 2, Folder 26)
  - Chess, 1976-1983 (journal, newsletters, articles, correspondence) (Box 2, Folder 27)
  - Chronological Incoming Mail, 1977-1979 (correspondence, reports) (Box 2, Folder 28)
  - Communications, 1971, 1976 (article, reports) (Box 2, Folder 29)
  - Computer Forum - Stanford Computer Forum, 1976-1978 (memos, agendas) (Box 2, Folder 30)
  - Crunching, 1976 (printouts) (Box 2, Folder 31)
  - CSD Computing - Computer Science Department, 1970-1979 (correspondence, reports, notes) (Box 2, Folder 32)
  - CSD Displays, 1976 (proposal, memos) (Box 2, Folder 33)
  - CSD Memos, 1974-1978 (memos, CSD Faculty Meeting Minutes) (Box 2, Folder 34)
  - CF Committee - Computation Facilities Committee, 1968-1977 (memos (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - minutes, reports) (Box 3)
  - Databases, 1974-1975 (reports, letter, printout) (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Defense of Vision - relevance to defense of computer vision related research (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Dishonesty, 1973-1979 (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Distributed Lab - Distributed National Laboratory for Cognitive Science, 1975 (proposal for NSF) (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Ecology, 1970-1977 (articles, newsletters, notes, reports, memos, brochure, letter) (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - EE Department - Electrical Engineering Department, 1976-1978 (memos, reports) (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Energy, 1974-1979 (reports, memos, newsletters, correspondence, articles, brochure on fusion) (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - Eng 235 - "An Alternative to the Petroleum Economy," 1973-1974 (course announcement, faculty list, memos, reprint, reports) (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - Environment, 1970-1976 (journal, letter, memo, brochure, articles, reprints, newsletter) (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - Essays, 1974-1976 (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - FOL, 1976-1978 (reports, a formalized proof using FOL) (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - Hand-Eye Current, 1975-1979 (correspondence, reports) research in Robot Languages and Stereo Vision Systems (Box 3, Folder 13)
  - KR 4, 1974 (computer-generated proof?) (Box 3, Folder 14)
  - LISP, 1977-1982 (newsletter, draft of manual, handwritten manual, programming instructions) (Box 3, Folder 15)
  - Optimism, 1974 (correspondence, articles) (Box 3, Folder 16)
  - Mail Terminal, 1977-1978 (articles, letter, newsletters) (Box 3, Folder 17)
  - Piano Mover, 1976-1977 (memos, flow charts) (Box 3, Folder 18)
  - Project Independence - project aimed at making the US substantially independent of foreign energy sources, 1974 (published letter, correspondence, position statement (Box 3, Folder 19)
  - Proofs, 1972-1976 (proof printouts) (Box 3, Folder 20)
  - SENSE - Scientists for Enlightenment on Nuclear Sources of Energy, 1975-1978 (correspondence, position statements, newsletters, articles) (Box 3, Folder 21)
  - S-1 - Computer processing system, 1977-1978 (articles, memos, correspondence, reports) (Box 3, Folder 22)
  - SE2 - Scientists and Engineers for Secure Energy, 1976-1980 (articles, correspondence, conference notes, brochure, legal brief, memos, reports) (Box 3, Folder 23)
  - SE2, 1980-1982 (memos, reports, legal briefs, correspondence, newsletters, articles) (Box 3, Folder 24)
  - SE2, 1978-1984 (correspondence, reports, reprints, articles, legal briefs, newsletters, minutes, by-laws, position/policy statements) (Box 3, Folder 25)
  - Social Articles, 1974-1978 (Box 3, Folder 26)
  - Soviet Jews, 1975-1978 (correspondence, memos, articles, newsletters, position statements) (Box 3, Folder 27)
  - Speaking Engagements, 1975-1984 (brochures, correspondence, expense reports, conference information, lecture transcription) (Box 3, Folder 28)
  - Student Advisees, 1982-1984 (correspondence, memos, printouts of student status, guidelines for dismissal) (Box 3, Folder 29)
  - Text Processing, 1979 (memo, draft for text processing project) (Box 3, Folder 30)
  - Time Sharing, 1959-1980 (report, correspondence) (Box 3, Folder 31)
  - Weizen - Weizenbaum, 1976-1977 (correspondence, articles) (Box 3, Folder 32)
  - Centre Mondiale, 1984-1985 (reports) (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Centre Mondiale, 1983-1985 ( reports, McCarthy proposal for an electronic library) (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Chandra, Ashok K., 1971 (program listing) (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - Cohen, Bernard L., 1978 (reports, article) (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - Creary, Lewis G., 1978-1982 (reports, article, reprint, resume) (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - CSLI, 1983 ( newsletters, memo) (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - Dahl, Veronica, 1981-1982 (correspondence) (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - Davis, Martin, 1976-1982 (correspondence, reports, articles, program listings?) (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - Dennett, Daniel, 1982 (draft of an article) (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - Deutsch, L. Peter, 1973 (article) (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - Diffie, Whitfield, 1970-1975 (letter, printout, article) (Box 4, Folder 11)
  - Dijkstra, Edsger W., 1978 ( article, correspondence) (Box 4, Folder 12)
  - Doyle, Jon, 1979-1983 ( correspondence, curriculum vitae) (Box 4, Folder 13)
  - Dreyfus, (article, manuscript) (Box 4, Folder 14)
  - University of Edinburgh, School of AI, 1971-1977, (department descriptions, technical memos) (Box 4, Folder 15)
  - Ershov, Andrei P., 1967-1982 (correspondence, articles, memos, interview) (Box 4, Folder 16)
  - Finite Fields, (mathematical notes, reprint, excerpt from book) (Box 4, Folder 17)
  - Hardware, 1977 (brochure, memo, article) (Box 4, Folder 18)
  - Home Terminals, 1974 (correspondence, memo) (Box 4, Folder 19)
  - IBM, 1974 (product announcement, brochure, articles, memo, notes) (Box 4, Folder 20)
  - IMSS, 1971-1974, (reprints, articles) (Box 4, Folder 21)
  - Inquiries, 1971-1975 (correspondence, article, resume) (Box 4, Folder 22)
  - Machine Translation, 1970-1971, (memos, article) (Box 4, Folder 23)
  - Memory, 1974 (articles, agenda-Advanced Memory Concepts Group) (Box 4, Folder 24)
  - Mining, 1974-1975 (conference brochure, article, proposal) (Box 4, Folder 25)
  - Money, 1971-1978 (articles, correspondence) (Box 4, Folder 26)
  - Names, 1972-1978 (lists, business cards, conference attendees, name jottings on paper, greeting cards) (Box 4, Folder 27)
  - Natural Language, 1973 (memo) (Box 4, Folder 28)
  - Network Journal - proposed ARPA network journal, 1972-1975 (memos, correspondence, articles, reprint) (Box 4, Folder 29)
  - Miscellaneous News Articles, 1976-1978 (Box 4, Folder 30)
  - NSF - National Science Foundation, 1971-1979 (articles, correspondence, memo, grant lists, NSF Proposal Guidelines, conference program) (Box 4, Folder 31)
  - NSF Reviews, 1977-1981 (Box 4, Folder 32)
  - Politics, 1970-1977 (articles, memos, correspondence) (Box 4, Folder 33)
  - Proposals, 1973-1977 (memos, correspondence, proposals) (Box 4, Folder 34)
  - Proposals, 1975-1978 (memo, letter, proposals) (Box 4, Folder 35)
  - Proposals, 1973-1977 (correspondence, memos, reports, proposals) (Box 4, Folder 36)
  - Public Affairs, 1970-1971 (newsletter, letter, newspaper, article) (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - Publicity, 1971-1977 (correspondence, articles) (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - Qual, AI - Qualifying Exam for AI, 1969-1975 (syllabi, exams, student scores, memo) (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - Qual, Comp - Comprehensive Qualifying Exam, 1972-1974 (memos, reading lists, exams, student scores, problem solutions) (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - Qual, MTC - PH.D. Qualifying Exam in Mathematical Theory of Computation, 1970-1974 (syllabi, exams) (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - Quarterly Report, 1972-1978 (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - Robotics, 1972-1978 (correspondence, articles, newsletter, brochure) (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - Rotation Number, (article) (Box 5, Folder 8)
  - RPV - Remotely Piloted Vehicles, 1973-1974, (memos, newsletters, correspondence, articles, symposium program) (Box 5, Folder 9)
  - Semantics, 1974 (articles) (Box 5, Folder 10)
  - SCIP, 1979 (memo, reports) (Box 5, Folder 11)
  - Technology, 1966-1973 (essay topic list, correspondence, questionnaire, articles) (Box 5, Folder 12)
  - Time-Sharing, 1974 (memos, article, reprint) (Box 5, Folder 13)
  - TSPP - Technology, Society and Public Policy, discussion group, 1975-1976, (memos, article) (Box 5, Folder 14)
  - WG2.2 - Working Group 2.2, 1974-1978, (minutes, newsletter, memos, agenda) (Box 5, Folder 15)
  - Weatherman, 1970-1978, (correspondence, articles, newspaper, journal, legal brief) (Box 5, Folder 16)
  - AI Journal, 1980-1982, (correspondence, abstracts, article, review status report) (Box 5, Folder 17)
  - AAAI from 8/83 - American Association for Artificial Intelligence, 1980-1984, (reports, correspondence, conference brochure, article) (Box 5, Folder 18)
  - Abramson, Fred, 1980-1981, (correspondence) (Box 5, Folder 19)
  - Aiello, Luigia, 1979, (article, resume) (Box 5, Folder 20)
  - Allen, J., 1974-1975, (correspondence, manuscript contents and index, article) (Box 5, Folder 21)
  - Anderson, B., 1972-1974, (correspondence, articles) (Box 5, Folder 22)
  - Anon, (articles) (Box 5, Folder 23)
  - Ashcroft, 1968-1969, (articles) (Box 5, Folder 24)
  - ATP Prize - Automatic Theorem Proving Prize, 1980-1982, (correspondence, article) (Box 5, Folder 25)
  - Babbage - The Charles Babbage Institute, 1979-1980, (correspondence, article, newsletters) (Box 5, Folder 26)
  - Barwise, Jon, (article) (Box 5, Folder 27)
  - Baskett, Forest, 1973-1978, (correspondence, article) (Box 5, Folder 28)
  - Binford, Tom, 1970-1987, (correspondence, curriculum vitae, recommendation for reappointment, reports, articles, charts) (Box 5, Folder 29)
  - Boeing, 1982-1983, (memos, correspondence, agreement) (Box 5, Folder 30)
  - Book - LISP: Programming and Proving, 1980-1872, (correspondence, letters of agreement, article, manuscript) (Box 5, Folder 31)
  - Kanerva, Pentti, 1975-1982, (memos, proposal, dissertation draft, article) (Box 5, Folder 32)
  - Konolige, Kurt, 1981-1985, (articles, thesis proposal, thesis drafts) (Box 5, Folder 33)
  - Knuth, Donald, 1969-1977, (correspondence, memo, reprints, article) (Box 5, Folder 34)
  - Kuo, Victor, 1982-1984, (correspondence, article, resume, memos) (Box 5, Folder 35)
  - Lamping, John, 1985, (article) (Box 5, Folder 36)
  - Lang, Serge, 1981-1985, (correspondence, article) (Box 5, Folder 37)
  - Lederberg. Joshua, 1974-1976, (articles, newsletter, correspondence, reprints) (Box 5, Folder 38)
  - Lem, Stanislaw, 1975, (correspondence, article) (Box 5, Folder 40)
  - Lenat, Douglas, 1974-1984, (correspondence, curriculum vitae, articles, course evaluations, report) (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - Lifschitz, Vladimir, 1984-1987, (articles) (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - Livermore, 1981-1983, (correspondence, employment application, personnel security questionnaire, consultant agreement, forms) (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - Luckham Letters, 1968-1977, (memos, correspondence, notes, articles, curriculum vitae, proposals, recommendation for appointment) (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - Milner, Robin, 1970-1974, (employee records, correspondence, articles, drafts of articles) (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - Martin, (dissertation proposal) (Box 6, Folder 6)
  - Michie, Donald, 1968-1981, (correspondence, brochure, articles, photograph, reprint) (Box 6, Folder 7)
  - McDermott, Drew, 1982, (letter, draft of article) (Box 6, Folder 8)
  - McCracken, Daniel, 1974, (letter, draft of article) (Box 6, Folder 9)
  - Marotta, David, 1981, (note, draft of article) (Box 6, Folder 10)
  - Moravec, Hans, 1969-1980, (correspondence, abstract, reprint) (Box 6, Folder 11)
  - Morris, Lockwood, 1968-1969, (articles, note, memo) (Box 6, Folder 12)
  - Moore, Robert, 1975, (articles, master's thesis) (Box 6, Folder 13)
  - Mints, Gregory, 1979-1980, (correspondence) (Box 6, Folder 14)
  - Minsky, Marvin, 1963-1973, (reprint, articles) (Box 6, Folder 15)
  - Minker, Jack, 1977, (letter, article) (Box 6, Folder 16)
  - Manna, Zohar, 1968-1979, (articles, correspondence, curriculum vitae, memos, reprints, proposal) (Box 6, Folder 17)
  - Malik, Jitendra, (article) (Box 6, Folder 18)
  - Maas, Robert, 1973, 1979, (article, program) (Box 6, Folder 19)
  - Ma Xiwen, 1978-1981, (correspondence, articles, curriculum vitae) (Box 6, Folder 20)
  - Polack, 1977, (proofs) (Box 6, Folder 21)
  - Papert, Seymour, 1970-1972, (letter, brochures, article, drafts of articles) (Box 6, Folder 22)
  - Parker, Edwin, 1974-1976, (newsletter, article) (Box 6, Folder 23)
  - Pednault, Edwin, 1981, (draft of article) (Box 6, Folder 24)
  - Pereira, Luis, 1981-1982, (correspondence, curriculum vitae, interview, articles, newsletter) (Box 6, Folder 25)
  - Perlis, Donald, 1982, (letter, resume, articles) (Box 6, Folder 26)
  - Philosophy, (article) (Box 6, Folder 27)
  - Oppen, Derek, 1975-1978, (letter, resume, articles) (Box 6, Folder 28)
  - Pack, Leslie, 1983, (programs, proof) (Box 6, Folder 29)
  - Nilsson, Nils, 1973-1985, (draft of proposal, correspondence, bibliography) (Box 6, Folder 30)
  - Sloman, Aaron, 1970-1981, (drafts of articles, correspondence, articles) (Box 7, Folder 1)
  - Sandewall, 1967-1980, (report, correspondence, articles) (Box 7, Folder 2)
  - Sato, Masahiko, 1976-1982, (correspondence, abstract, reprint, articles) (Box 7, Folder 3)
  - SE2, 1984, (article, correspondence, draft of article) (Box 7, Folder 4)
  - Shapiro, Ehud, 1982, (curriculum vitae, correspondence, report) (Box 7, Folder 5)
  - Shockley, William, 1975-1976, (articles, correspondence, reprints) (Box 7, Folder 6)
  - Stallman, 1981, (article, draft of article) (Box 7, Folder 7)
  - Space, 1981-1983, (correspondence, article, reports, newesletter) (Box 7, Folder 8)
  - Moser, Yoram, 1982-1985, (letter, articles, reprints) (Box 7, Folder 9)
  - Moses, Joel (article) (Box 7, Folder 10)
  - Moszkowski, Ben, 1977-1982, (article, letter, notes) (Box 7, Folder 11)
  - Nagao, Makoto, 1985, (letter, list) (Box 7, Folder 12)
  - SRI, 1971-1983, (reports - a series called technical notes) (Box 7, Folder 13)
  - Samet, Hanan, 1975 (dissertation) (Box 7, Folder 14)
  - Samet, Hanan, 1972-1975, (program listing, articles) (Box 7, Folder 15)